Tatiana Didik

- cell 347-429-5570 e-mail: tatiana.didik.0@gmail.com •
- US Visa Status: GC Current Location: Weehawken, NJ (NYC Area) •

Software Engineer

A passionate back-end developer, a team-worker, who undertakes complex assignments, meets tight deadlines and delivers great performance. Result- and quality-oriented specialist, open to new technologies and business challenges. Experienced in development, UAT, Go Live, support / maintenance, and multi-customer shift stages of a SaaS project.

Core Competencies

\checkmark	Java SE	\checkmark	JDBC	\checkmark	Jenkins	\checkmark	Swing UI
\checkmark	SQL	\checkmark	Hibernate	\checkmark	JIRA	\checkmark	HTML
\checkmark	JBoss	\checkmark	SVN	\checkmark	UML	\checkmark	CSS
✓	Maven	✓	Git	\checkmark	XML	\checkmark	JavaScript

Certifications

Oracle Certified Associate	Java SE 7 Programmer I	90%	January 2015
Oracle Certified Professional	Java SE 7 Programmer II	86%	February 2015
IELTS General	L 7.5 R 9.0 W 7.0 S 6.5	7.5/9.0	September 2016

Professional Experience

MAGENTA TECHNOLOGY / Echo / Software Engineer (Full Time)

May 2010 – June 2014

Project: **Echo**¹ is a Microsoft Gold Partner award winning ² taxi dispatch enterprise software written in Java. The project is managed with Apache Maven, is based on relational database (MS SQL), accessed with Hibernate JPA via JBoss application server. Inventory used on this project includes JIRA as bug-tracking system, SVN for version control, TeamCity for continuous integration process. All the above were used on daily basis.

Responsibilities and achievements

- ✓ Implemented new software modules in accordance with functional specifications:
 - Developed from scratch a module for driver salary processing, allowing authorized users to generate configurable payment reports (powered by Jasper Reports) automatically or semimanually, close a payment period or reopen it for amendments (until it is processed by a bank system). The report's content is fully configurable from Java Swing based UI;
 - Implemented a module for dynamic delay calculation³ allowing customers to get up-to-date information regarding their taxi's arrival time, and taxi company to improve their performance by rescheduling related rides according to this information. This module is a part of the award-winning scheduling and auto-allocating features;
 - Developed a template module allowing partnering with external taxi aggregators used by corporate accounts and composing about 20% of corporate bookings⁴ in total;
 - Implemented an integration⁵ with One Transport taxi consolidator using SOAP web protocol now supplying businesses powered by Echo with thousands of cars monthly (the integration is based on the previously mentioned module).
- ✓ Participated hands-on in functional specification design:
 - Contributed into system redesign allowing partnering companies such as greentomatocars and Trident Niven to share their resources and employees. This partnership allowed the companies to decrease by 13%⁶ the out-sourcing of spilling-over bookings;
 - Was involved in functional specification design for mentioned above modules along with business analyst.
- ✓ Improved custom Java Swing UI framework:
 - Developed a mechanism allowing locating of UI memory leaks (unnecessary allocation of huge amounts of memory) automatically using Test Complete to emulate highly loaded use of the application and heap dump generation when necessary. After detailed heap dump

Tatiana Didik 1/2

- analysis with JProfiler, added a mechanism for destroying circular links, preventing Java garbage collector from reclaiming unused objects, that dramatically reduced RAM allocation by the application:
- Invented a mechanism allowing highlighting of editable fields in accordance with input validation needs:
- Was in charge for the whole project's Java Swing UI framework.
- ✓ Participated in bugfixing, troubleshooting, maintenance and technical support of previously developed modules.

JENKINS / Sonar-Gerrit Plugin / Open-Source Contribution

2015 - CURRENT

✓ Developed, documented and maintained a plugin for Jenkins⁷, allowing to post SonarQube report data as a Gerrit review. It is currently downloaded more than 1100 times⁸ and used on software development projects worldwide.

SSAU / Course Project

2011 - 2012

Development of information technology for project's estimated time costs calculation

✓ Design and development of a time management tool allowing to calculate estimated time costs for a complicated task set using UML for visualization, probability laws for estimation and a neural network for the process emulation.

Education

SAMARA STATE AEROSPACE UNIVERSITY / Samara, Russia Applied mathematics & informatics BS & MS

MS <u>2010 – 2012</u> BS <u>2006 – 2010</u>

- Discrete Math Math Statistics and Probability Theory Math Analysis Algebraic Structures ●
- Computer Telecommunications
 Parallel Computation and Programming
 Numerical Methods
 - Distributed DB and Expert Systems
 Math Modeling
 Math Methods of Cryptography

Links

- linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tatianadidik
 hakerrank: https://www.hackerrank.com/aquarellian
 - stakoverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/7111382/tatiana-didik
 - github: https://github.com/aguarellian •

Tatiana Didik 2/2

¹ Magenta / Echo: project web page: https://magenta-technology.com/echo

² Magenta / Echo: Microsoft Gold Partner award news: https://magenta-technology.com/blog/2016/08/08/magenta-technology-gets-microsoft-gold-for-echo-taxi-and-private-hire-dispatch-software

³ Magenta / Echo: dynamic delays are mentioned in https://youtu.be/gqUy4VIYqoI?t=224 and explained in https://magenta-technology.com/blog/2016/09/12/are-all-apps-really-equal

⁴ Magenta / Echo: Booking sources statistics: https://magenta-technology.com/echo#corporate

⁵ Magenta / Echo: integration details: https://magenta-technology.com/echo#integration and https://m

⁶ Magenta / Echo: Two of Transdev's businesses (greentomatocars and Trident Niven) collaborate with empowerment of shared application instance https://magenta-technology.com/blog/2014/09/10/trident-niven-improves-efficiency-and-reduces-communication-traffic-by-60-with-magentas-taxi-dispatch-and-private-hire-software

⁷ Jenkins is the leading open source automation server for continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) https://jenkins.io/

⁸ Sonar-Gerrit plugin webpage is https://plugins.jenkins.io/sonar-gerrit, current installations statistics shown on https://stats.jenkins.io/plugin-installation-trend/sonar-gerrit.stats.json